Dion Tu

38 Foxfield Crescent, L4K 5G1, Vaughan, ON

(416) 274-8571 | diontu1@gmail.com | github.com/diontu | linkedin.com/in/diontu/

Summary_

Software engineer with 3 years of web development experience, designing and implementing frontend and backend solutions within an Agile environment. At Scotiabank, I co-led my team, delivering end-to-end flows of 2 frontend applications with error handling. Continuously satisfied business requirements through delivering features with emphasis on code quality and maintainability. I have an interest towards the latest technologies, developing maintainable code and am actively seeking ways to optimize frontend experiences.

Skills_

Programming Languages: JavaScript (React, React Native, Node.js, AngularJS), Java (Spring), HTML, CSS.

Databases: SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MongoDB.

Others: Git, GitHub, Docker, Amazon Web Services (S3, EC2), Jira, Confluence, WordPress.

Education

Lassonde School of Engineering, York University

Toronto, ON 09/2017-05/2021

Honours Bachelor of Engineering, Software Engineering

· Graduated May 2021.

Work Experience_____

Software Engineer I

Toronto, ON

Scotiabank 07/2021–Present

- Designed and developed 2 multi-step frontend applications, payment creation and approval, for corporate and commercial banking using React, Redux Toolkit, and CSS.
- · Co-led a team of 4 to deliver end-to-end flow of the payment creation and approval applications with error handling.
- Developed and presented a solution to introduce a modal popup in the parent application of a micro-frontend architecture that hosted 15+ micro-frontend applications.
- · Actively contributed to Scotiabank's standard UI components library to improve user's experience and interaction.
- · Implemented Java APIs for consumption, using Spring.
- Worked closely with product owners to implement required and suggested features, while discussing limitations and suggested solutions.
- Written more lines of code for tests than for features using Jest and React Testing Library.

Developer, Co-op

Toronto, ON

TD Bank 05/2019–08/2019

- Developed solutions for frontend error handling using AngularJS, Spring Boot, and MySQL.
- Collaborated with team members to identify and resolve bugs, reducing backlog work items by 5%.
- Worked closely with business stakeholders to maintain an internal business web application, with emphasis on addressing user feedback.
- Worked with Quality Assurance to ensure functionality is expected.

Projects_____

CarePilot 09/2020-04/2021

- Developed a mobile solution for effective communication between patients and their families within a hospital setting, using React Native and Firestore.
- Transformed requirements into deliverable solutions. Carried out a technical roadmap detailing the work items and their acceptance criteria, using Azure DevOps to keep track of development progress.
- Planned and carried out Agile Scrum methodology with sprint planning, reviews, and retrospectives.

Certifications